(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-14T22:39:20.663536",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey!
ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
寒々 夜の帳
Under the chilly veil of night,
凍る言葉受け流して
brushing off freezing words,
彗星を待ってた
I was waiting for a comet.
光には大層な覚悟で
Prepared with immense resolve for the light,
それでも輝きへと手を伸ばしたい
I still want to reach out toward the radiance,
それには暴れる夢がいた
and within me, a wild dream was raging.
今は 今は名も無き 花以前の蕾だと
For now, I'm just a nameless bud before blooming,
冬の嵐を耐えながら描くよ
so enduring winter's storm, I envision it,
情熱落とさぬままで
without letting my passion fade.
泣きそうな時は泣いてしまえ
When you feel like crying, just let it all out,
それが未来咲かす 魁となれ
and let that become the harbinger to bloom our future.
瞳の純度は上がることになるから
Because the clarity in your eyes will only grow purer,
無駄になんかならない
it will never be in vain.
泣きそうな時は泣いてしまえ
When you feel like crying, just let it all out,
今日はそんな日もあると笑って
smile and say today was just that kind of day.
涙と混ぜ 希望よそんな感じ
Mingled with tears, that's what hope feels like,
華麗に咲き誇る前哨戦
the prelude to blooming in full, gorgeous glory.
Ha!
悲しみながら虎視眈々
While feeling sorrow, vigilantly watching and waiting,
全身化して背水の陣
giving it my all with my back against the wall.
気後れせず 雲を穿つ 負けてない 枯れてない 1, 2, 3
Unfazed, piercing the clouds— undefeated, unwithered, one, two, three!
一つじゃない 幾つも願い叶えたい
Not just one, there are so many wishes I want to fulfill,
尖り走るやっとの水星
sharply streaking at last, like a comet.
叫びへと変わる祈り
A prayer turning into a scream,
それなら届きそうだ
if it's like that, it feels like it can reach.
掴んで見せ それから
I'll grasp it, and after that,
散らない夢を見よう
let's dream a dream that never scatters.
されどされど名も無き 花の胸の誇りは
Yet still, the pride in the heart of a nameless flower
この世の何より尊いと思うよ
is more precious than anything in this world, I believe.
誰も 誰も知らなくても
Even if no one, no one knows,
我思う故の自分
I think, therefore I am myself!
泣いちゃった分だけ僕よ逞しく
Grow stronger, me, by as much as I cried!
もっともっと なんて欲張りかい
"More and more"—is that being too greedy?
欲張りじゃない願いだ 願いの強さが喉を射て
It's not greed, it's a wish— the strength of this wish pierces my throat.
泣いちゃった分だけ僕よ逞しく
Grow stronger, me, by as much as I cried!
優雅に咲き魁となれ
Bloom gracefully and become the trailblazer!
現世浮世 祭祀の野望に乗って
In this fleeting world, riding upon ambitious rites,
麗しく咲かせよ心
make your heart bloom beautifully!
泣きそうな時は泣いてしまえ それが未来開花
When you feel like crying, just cry— that's the blooming of the future!
魁となれ
Become the trailblazer!
瞳の温度は上がり続けるよ
The warmth in my eyes keeps rising.
咲き誇れるわ もうちょっと
I can bloom in full glory, just a little more!
麗しく咲かせよ心
Make your heart bloom beautifully!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Thank you!
あの日描いて 本当の言葉を
Painting the true words from that day,
生きている鼓動を
and the pulse that beats with life...
痛みながら ただ消えぬように
While hurting, just so it doesn't disappear,
まだ息をしたい理由があるの
I still have a reason to keep breathing.
不可視 / 作詞・作曲：ユリイ・カノン
[Invisible / Lyrics & Music: YurryCanon]
幸せだけを選んでいたって 先は見えない
Even if I only chose happiness, I wouldn't see what lies ahead.
過ぎ去った今を 仕方ないなんて 許せればいいけど
If only I could forgive the past, brushing it off as "it can't be helped"...
嘘でまた 並べられる夢じゃない
But it's not a dream that can be lined up with lies again.
あの日描いて 本当の言葉を
Painting the true words from that day,
生きている鼓動を
and the pulse that beats with life...
闇に迷うのは ひとつじゃない道があるから
The reason I get lost in darkness is because there isn't just one path.
欠けて 求めて また傷が増えて
Lacking, searching, getting hurt again and again,
全て捨て去れば 痛みなどない
if I threw it all away, there would be no pain.
でも 立ち尽くすだけじゃ見られない 明日があるの
But there is a tomorrow I can't see just by standing still.
満ちていた日が いつか訪れると思っていた
I used to think the fulfilled days would come someday.
誰も同じと 一人言い訳しては目を逸らした
Making excuses to myself that "everyone's the same," I looked away.
喉につかえた 言葉飲み込んでしまって
Swallowing down the words caught in my throat,
本当のことも隠しては嘘と
hiding the truth away as lies.
声を殺した 心を目隠しして
I hushed my voice, blindfolding my heart.
継ぎ接ぎの姿 生きてると言えるだろうか
In this patched-up state, can I even say that I'm alive?
Ah...
だから
So,
不安の針に気付いてよ
please notice the needle of anxiety.
触れては失って 恐れては耐えて 枯れてしまうけど
Touching and losing, fearing and enduring, even if I wither away,
転ばぬより 傷が増えても
rather than never falling, even if more scars form,
前に進んだんじゃない
isn't it proof that I've moved forward?
あの日...
From that day...
抱き寄せて 本当の言葉を
Pull me close and hear my true words,
消えていく鼓動を
as my fading heartbeat...
どうか どうか その目に映して
...please, oh please, reflect it in your eyes,
また夢を見よう
and let's dream once again.
私も怖いけど
I'm scared too, but...
君がいれば
...as long as you are here.
というわけで、みなさん！
And with that, everyone!
こやぴー！
Koyapi~!
はい、ホロライブ4期生の常闇トワです！
Yes, I'm Hololive 4th Gen's Tokoyami Towa!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ということで、本日は、えー、生誕祭、あ！
So, today is... my Birthday Live, ah!
今日はね、トワちゃんの誕生日なんです！ハッピーバースデー、えー、トワ、to トワということで。
Today is Towa-chan's birthday! "Happy Birthday to Towa," as they say!
えー、お誕生日と、and そして！and そして！
Um, my birthday, and also! And also!
何回言うんだよって。えー、なんと新衣装の
Like, how many times will I say it? We also have...
お披露目もあります！イェーイ！
...a new outfit reveal! Yay!
えー、100万人記念をね、使って、あのー新衣装を作っていただきましたー！
Um, to celebrate hitting 1 million subscribers, they made a new outfit for me!
イェーイ！
Yay!
そしてね、今日のライブなんですが、ミニライブになっておりまして、
And about today's show, it's a mini-live concert,
だいたい30分...いって40分ぐらいで終わるんじゃないかなと思ってるんですけれども、
so I think it'll last around 30 minutes... maybe 40 minutes at most, but...
その短い時間でも楽しんでいただければなと思います！
...I hope you have a great time even during this short duration!
お願いしまーす！
Please enjoy!
はい。で、今回は、えっと、スープさんというね会社にね、手伝ってもらって、
Yes. And this time, a company called SOUP helped us out,
今日のライブを作ってまーす！
to put together today's live!
スープさんありがとうー！
Thank you, SOUP!
そしてね、これ収録なんですけれども、え、収録の日に、なんかスープさんから、
Also, this is pre-recorded, and on the day of recording, someone from SOUP told me...
「なんかトコヤミ祭に応募したんですけど外れました」みたいな、
..."I applied for tickets to Tokoyami-sai, but didn't win," or something like that,
ことを言われて、「えっ？知らなかったんだけど。応募してたんだ？ウケる」っつって、
and I was like, "Eh? I had no idea. You applied? That's hilarious!"
もう何回も面白くなってるんですけどね。ちょっとプチ笑いというか。
It keeps cracking me up every time. Just a little funny moment.
ということで、えー、今日はね、さっきも言った通り、新衣装、3Dの新衣装もありますし、
So, as I said earlier, today we have a new outfit—a 3D new outfit—
他にもなんと発表がありますので、
and there are also other big announcements,
ぜひ最後までここに居座り続けてください！
so please stick around right here until the very end!
はい！
Alright!
で、そしてハッシュタグのお知らせです。
And now, here's an announcement about the hashtag.
ピッ。こちら！
*Beep.* Right here!
はい。「#常闇トワ生誕祭2026」になりますので、
Yes! It's "#TokoyamiTowaBirthday2026,"
えー、ぜひたくさん感想をポストしてくださいね。
so please post lots of your impressions!
えー、美人の写真のスクリーンショットも待っておりますよー。
I'm also waiting for your screenshots of this beauty!
はい。
Yes.
はい。で、えっと、曲の振り返りなんですが、
Okay. Now, to recap the songs so far:
えー、1曲目が『魁』を、ファーストソロライ...ライブの、
For the first song, "Sakigake,"
うー、ファーストソロライブの衣装を着て歌わせていただきました。
I sang it wearing my 1st Solo Live outfit.
え、そして2曲目はですね、えー、『不可視』を、
And for the second song, "Fukashi,"
えー、セカンドソロライブの衣装で歌わせていただきましたー！イェーイ！
I performed it in my 2nd Solo Live outfit! Yay!
あのー、そこまで意図してなかったんだけど、どちらの曲もね、ソロライブの、
I hadn't really planned it this way, but both of those songs...
一番さい...本当に最後の最後の、アンコールの最後の曲だったんですよー！
...were the absolute final songs—the very last songs of the encore at each solo live!
もうどっちもね、好きだから入れただけなんですけど。
I just included them because I love both songs, though.
はい。なんか、この収録をしてるときに、どっちのソロライブの景色がね、
Yes. While recording this, memories and sights from both solo lives...
思い浮かんで、ちょっとエモかったです。はい。
...came to mind, and it felt really emotional. Yeah.
ぜひBlu-rayも発売してるので、チェックしてくださいねー！
The Blu-rays are on sale, so be sure to check them out!
はい。
Yes!
そして、次なんですけれども、
And moving on to the next part,
えー、なんと先日ソロライブを終えたあの、超超超超超大物ゲストと一緒に歌っちゃいます！
I'll be singing with that super, super, super, super big guest who just finished her solo live!
えー、こちらは、
And that is...
まあもう言っちゃうと、ねねちが、ねねち？ねねねが来てくれまーす！
Well, to just say it: Nenechi—Nenechi? Nenene is here!
ねねねとね、えー、先日6月28日に、なんと...まあこれ、なんか、もう受け入れてる形にはなってるんだけど、
Recently on June 28th, Nenene and I... well, I've just kind of accepted it at this point, but...
「ねねねトワはカップル4周年記念」
"Nenene and Towa's 4th Couple Anniversary"!
ねねね、カップル？ねねトワ4周年記念になりまして、
Nenene... couple? It was NeneTowa's 4th anniversary,
そこで初めてオリ曲を出したんですよ。
and we released our very first original song together!
その曲をね、えー、今日はダンスフルバージョンでお届けしたいと思います！
Today, we'd like to perform that song for you with full choreography!
えー、『#ウチらしか勝たん』、どうぞ！
"#UchirashikaKatan," please enjoy!
盛れてる角度で 切り取る今日って
Capturing today from the most flattering angle,
でもそれだけじゃ なんかつまんないでしょ？
but wouldn't it be kinda boring with just that?
拍手喝采 もっとちょうだい
Give us even more applause and cheers!
はいはい こちらに注目
Yes, yes, all eyes over here!
キュートなだけじゃ終われない
We won't just stop at being cute.
でも少しくらい甘えたい
But we still want to be pampered just a little.
私をポップアップした画面越しのスター
The star beyond the screen that you popped up—
そう簡単にさ 触れさせはしないの
I won't let you touch me that easily!
ねえ こっちに来たいんでしょ？
Hey, you want to come over here, don't you?
隣にいてほしいんでしょ？
You want me by your side, don't you?
ねえ もっと見たいんでしょ？
Hey, you want to see more, don't you?
私が欲しいんでしょ？
You want me all to yourself, don't you?
完全優勝でしょ
Total victory, without a doubt!
まだまだ足りない 私へのLike
Still not enough Likes for me!
単純明快な世界
In this simple and clear world,
いや まだ足りない 貰い足りない
No, it's still not enough, haven't received enough!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん 私しか勝たん
We win, we win, we win, nobody beats me!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん ウチらしか勝たん
We win, we win, we win, nobody beats us!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん 私しか勝たん
We win, we win, we win, nobody beats me!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん ウチらしか勝たん
We win, we win, we win, nobody beats us!
落ちてるライトで塗り替える今日
Repainting today with the falling lights,
でも綺麗なだけじゃ oh no no
But just being pretty is an "oh no no."
つまんないでしょ 想像以上のショー
That'd be boring, right? A show beyond your imagination—
期待以上を見せてほしいの
I want you to show me more than expected!
ねえ もっと近づきたいんでしょ？
Hey, you want to get closer, don't you?
本音まで知りたいんでしょ？
You want to know my true feelings, don't you?
ねえ もっと目離せないんでしょ？
Hey, you can't take your eyes off me, right?
私しかいないでしょ？
There's no one else for you but me, right?
断然本命でしょ
Hands down your clear favorite, right?
まだまだ足りない 私へのLike
Still not enough Likes for me!
絶対運命でしょ
Definitely our destiny, right?
いや まだ足りない 愛足りない
No, it's still not enough, not enough love!
その目の奥 見つめたいの
I want to gaze into the depths of your eyes,
その熱ごと欲しくなるの
I start craving all that heat.
正解なんて要らないの
I don't need the "right answer."
ねえ 本当を聞かせて
Hey, tell me the real truth.
完全優勝でしょ
Total victory, without a doubt!
まだまだ足りない 私へのLike
Still not enough Likes for me!
絶対運命でしょ
Definitely our destiny, right?
いや まだ足りない 愛足りない
No, it's still not enough, not enough love!
全然足りない 貰い足りない
Nowhere near enough, haven't received enough!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん 私しか勝たん
We win, we win, we win, nobody beats me!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん ウチらしか勝たん
We win, we win, we win, nobody beats us!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん 私しか勝たん
We win, we win, we win, nobody beats me!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん ウチらしか勝たん
We win, we win, we win, nobody beats us!
はい！ということで、ねねねトワで「ウチらしか勝たん」でしたー！
Alright! So that was "Uchira Shika Katan" performed by Nenene-Towa!
どうだったでしょうか？
How did you like it?
ダンス、頑張りました！
We worked really hard on the dance!
ねね、ありがとうー！
Nene, thank you so much!
はい。ちょっとギャルっぽい感じでね、
Yeah. It had a bit of a gyaru vibe to it,
振り付けもね、えー、愛理先生に作ってもらいましたー！
and the choreography was created for us by Airi-sensei!
元々はね、「勝たん勝たん」が結構好きで、
I originally really liked the "katan katan" part,
このピースのとこ。「勝たん、勝たん、勝たん」
this peace sign part: "Katan, katan, katan."
これがね、ギャルっぽくて可愛くて、すごい好きです。
It's so gyaru-esque and cute, I really love it.
ぜひ踊ってみてね。
You should definitely try dancing it too!
踊ってみてね、むずいな。
Though "try dancing it" might be pretty tough...
はい。ぜひね、あの、いっぱい繰り返し見てもらえればなと思います！
Yes! I really hope you'll watch it over and over again!
聴いてね、曲も！
Be sure to listen to the song, too!
はーい。
Alright!
ということで！
And with that!
えー、お待たせいたしました！
Thank you all for waiting!
この後は！
Coming up next...
常闇トワちゃん、
Tokoyami Towa's...
新...新...3D...あ、違う。
New... new... 3D... ah, no.
3D新衣装の発表ー！
The reveal of my new 3D outfit!
ということで、
And so,
着替えてきたいと思います！
I'm going to go get changed!
着替えまーす。
Off to change!
あ、じゃ、着替えますからね。
Ah, well, I'm going to get changed now.
着替えますからね！
I'm getting changed, alright?!
うんしょ、うんしょ、と。
Heave-ho, heave-ho...
はぁ...大変だ。
Phew... this is tough.
すごい、やっぱり...うー、うおー！
Wow, seriously... oof, whoa!
どんなだよということで。着替えました！
What kind of reaction was that? Anyway, I'm changed!
では、いいですか？行きますよ、皆さん！
Now then, are you ready? Here I come, everyone!
行きますよ！
Here we go!
なんかザーボンさん、ドドリアさん来た。
Wait, here come Zarbon and Dodoria...
は、あ、やばい。あ、美しい足が...
Ah, oh shoot. Ah, my gorgeous legs...
美しい足が出ております！
...my gorgeous legs are now on display!
ちょっとバランスが取りづらい。
It's a bit tricky to keep my balance.
どう？ほら！
How is it? Look!
まず、この足。
First, these legs.
なんか最近のさ、流行りなのよ、この薄々の靴下。
These sheer socks are super trendy lately.
これ、名前なんていうのか分かんないけど。
I don't know what they're actually called though.
え、新衣装ね、rurudo先生に描いていただいたんですけども、
Um, for the new outfit, it was designed by rurudo-sensei,
先生のね、あの、センスが良すぎて、私には
but sensei's sense of fashion is so good that
この名前が何なのかというのは分からないんですが、
I don't really know the exact terms for these,
でも、こんな感じに足はなってますよ。
but this is what the legs look like!
イラストレーターの皆さん、必見でございます！
To all the illustrators out there, this is a must-see!
ね、待って、リボンも可愛くない？ほら！
Wait, aren't the ribbons super cute too? Look!
あ、いいですねカメラさん。いいですねー。
Ah, nice work, camera person. Looking good~.
ほらほら。
Look, look.
はい、じゃあ段々上に上がって...
Alright, let's slowly pan up...
ズーン
Zooming in...
ちょっとスカートの...
Up to around the skirt...
あ、やべ、スカートって言っちゃった。え、スカートじゃない。
Ah shoot, I said skirt! Ah, not a skirt.
のとこまで！
...up to here!
やー、ストップ！
Yeah, stop!
はい！
Alright!
スカート、こんな感じになってます。
The skirt looks like this.
スカートというか、これなんて言うか...
Or rather than a skirt, what should I call this...
一応ズボンなんですよねー。
It's basically shorts, you know?
はい。で、見て？
Alright. And look at this?
可愛くない？
Isn't it cute?
ビビ、ビビのキーホルダーだ。
Bibi, it's a Bibi keychain.
むにゃむにゃむにゃむにゃ...
Squish, squish, squish...
可愛い！
So cute!
むにゃむにゃむにゃ...
Squish, squish, squish...
はい、キーホルダーが付いてたりとか、
Yep, there's a keychain attached,
ちゃんと尻尾が出るようになってたりとか、
and my tail can stick out properly,
しております。
like this.
そして見てください。
And please look at this.
ネイルと指輪！
The nails and rings!
アクセサリー。
Accessories.
ほら、こんな感じです。
Look, it's like this.
うん、ちょっとギャルで可愛いでしょ？
Yeah, kind of gyaru and cute, right?
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい。で、これで多分みんなスクリーンショットしたから、
Alright. And since everyone probably took screenshots of this,
え、ネイルま...
the nails...
意外とトワのネイル真似する人いっぱいいるんでしょ？だから、
Surprisingly, a lot of people copy Towa's nails, right? So,
このネイルを多分真似してくれるでしょう！
they'll probably copy these nails too!
はい、ということでちょっと見えてきちゃってますけれども、ちょっと首のところまで、
Alright, so it's starting to show a bit, but up to the neck...
じゃあ、上げて上げて...
let's go up, go up...
だ、うわー！
da— Woah!
やばい、髪の毛が...なんか長くなーい？ちょっと髪の毛長くなーい？
Oh no, the hair... isn't it kind of long? Isn't my hair a bit long?
なんかちょっとオバサンみたいな言い方になってる。
I sounded like an old lady just now.
はい。で、これがジャケットですね。
Alright. And this is the jacket.
ジャケットに、ちょっと透け感があるトップスにということで、
A jacket over a slightly sheer top, and so...
はい、腕には「TOWA」と、「常闇トワ」と書いてあります。
Yes, on the sleeve it says "TOWA", "Tokoyami Towa".
こっちは何にもない。
There's nothing on this side.
はい、ちょっと後ろ見ちゃうと...
Alright, if we look at the back...
なんかストレートじゃない？髪の毛が。
Doesn't my hair look straight?
ということで、上まで行っちゃいますか！
So then, shall we go all the way up!
はい、ドーン！
Here we go, bam!
ジャーーン！
Tadaaa!
ということで、帽子も付いてたりして、
And so, there's a cap too,
こんな感じです！
and it looks like this!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい、どうでしょう？
Alright, what do you think?
はい、今撮るとこですよー。
Right now is your screenshot time!
はい、撮るとこですよー。
Yep, time to take photos!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい！
Alright!
そう、今回キャップ、キャップなんです。
That's right, this time it's a cap, a cap!
ちょっとストリート系というか、なんていうか。
Kind of street style, or something like that.
でしょう？であとは、
Right? And also,
こっちだ。
this one.
ギャルっぽいキラキラ付いてまーす！
There are gyaru-like sparkle chains!
これもセンスが高すぎて、よく分かってないけど付いてるやつ！
This is another thing where the sense is so high-level that I don't really get it, but it's on there!
最悪だよ、自分についてるのに！
That's terrible, considering I'm the one wearing it!
センスがすごすぎるんですよね。
The sense of style is just way too amazing.
ちょっとあのー、デザインしてもらうとびっくりします。おしゃれすぎて。
When they design for me, I'm always amazed by how fashionable it is.
で、あとちょっとカッコイイめのパールとチェーンのネックレス付けたりとか、
And then I'm also wearing a cool pearl and chain necklace,
しております。
like this.
裏はこんな感じ。
The back looks like this.
お？
Oh?
はい。
Alright.
では！
Now then!
なんと！この帽子、取れちゃうんです！
Guess what! This cap comes off!
ちょっと帽子取ってきますね。
I'll go take off the cap, okay?
ふぅ。
Phew.
取れました！帽子。
I took it off! The cap.
すごいでしょ？
Amazing, right?
もう日差しを直接受けてしまいます。
Now I'll be exposed directly to the sunlight.
っていうのは置いといて、はい！
Jokes aside, okay!
白いね、メッシュが付いてたりとか、
There are white highlights in my hair,
このキラキラしてるのが付いてたりとか、
and these sparkling chains,
あと、今回はハーフ...ハーフアップというか、ハーフアップじゃないけど、これ三つ編みで
and also, this time it's half... not quite a half-up, but it's braided with three strands
編み込みしてもらって、後ろ、
woven in, and in the back,
可愛く結んでます。
it's tied up cutely.
こんな感じです。
It looks like this.
これちゃんとね、イラストレーターさんのみんながバーッと描いてくれるのを楽しみにしてるんで、
I'm really looking forward to all the illustrators drawing this,
ゆっくり見せてます。
so I'm showing it slowly.
あとは、いつも通りピアスがバチバチ付いてたりしてます。
And also, as usual, I have a bunch of piercings.
はい！で、今...
Alright! And now...
ちょっとまだジャケット着てるんですけれども、
I'm still wearing the jacket, but...
このジャケットを脱ぐと...あ、脱ぐことができるんですよ。脱ぐとどうなるか、
when I take off this jacket... ah, it can be removed, you see. What happens when I take it off...
見せたいと思います。
I want to show you!
この名残惜しく出るのにはまってるのかもしれない。
Maybe I'm getting hooked on exiting so lingeringly.
うずわあああ！
Ozuwaaaa!
えー、この叫び声。
Um, that scream...
あ、こんな感じです！
Ah, it looks like this!
この、え、20キロあるジャケットを脱ぎました！
I took off this 20-kilo jacket!
あ、帽子は30キロありました。
Ah, the cap was 30 kilos.
すごい、今首が軽いです。
My neck feels so light right now.
ということで！こんな感じ！
And so! It's like this!
このさ、トワがワーワー言ってる間ね、スタジオはすっごいシーンとしてるからすっごい恥ずかしいんだよ！
You know, while Towa is screaming and carrying on, the studio is dead silent, so it's super embarrassing!
はい、見てください。
Alright, please look.
腕のアクセサリーがこんな感じで。しかも、
The arm accessories are like this. And what's more,
タトゥーがここに入っちゃってます！
there's a tattoo right here!
そして、こっち。
And on this side,
こっちもカッコイイアクセサリーを腕に付けております。
I've got cool accessories on this arm too.
はい！で、こんな感じです！
Alright! And it looks like this!
はい、これでも写真撮ってくださいね！
Yep, take photos of this too, okay!
イェーイ！
Yay!
イェーイ
あ、分かった
Ah, I got it.
これや、まず。はい
First, this one! Here.
これね、写真撮ってね、みんな
Take pictures of this, everyone!
はい！
Here!
T
あ、Tじゃない。これ言っちゃダメだ、これ
Ah, not "T"! I shouldn't say it!
あ、P。はい！
Ah, "P"! Here!
こんな感じです
It looks like this.
イェーイ！
Yay!
後ろも？
The back too?
はい、こんな感じ。すっきりするよね、ジャケットないだけで
Here's how it looks. It feels much cleaner just without the jacket, right?
はい。で、まだ更にあるんです
Right. And there's even more!
実は、この上、黒のトップス...
Actually, this top... the black top...
色変わるんです。虹色に
changes color! To rainbow!
ちょっと待っててください
Please wait a second.
えーっと、塗り替えて、と
Let's see, repainting this...
でもう終わったから...
And it's already done, so...
うわ、出てきた
Whoa, here I come.
はい！
Here!
ジャジャーン！虹色ではないです！
Ta-da! It's not rainbow!
白です！
It's white!
だから上と下、白白にすることができるんですよね
So you can make both the top and bottom all white!
はい、どうでしょう？
Alright, what do you think?
で、まだね、他にも実は組み合わせがあるんで
And there are actually other combinations too,
どの組み合わせが良かったのか、後で教えてください
so tell me later which combination you liked best!
はい、で、あ、これスクショしてくださいね。はい、はいスクショタイム
Right, and make sure to take a screenshot of this. Screenshot time!
この時点で何がしたいのか分かった人...
Whoever figured out what I'm trying to do at this point...
静かに、ですよ
keep it quiet, okay?
はい！
Alright!
では、そしてね、なんと...
Now then, and guess what...
下もね...
The bottom too...
実は...変わるんですよ！
actually... changes too!
シュールすぎる。たまには反対側帰れよ、みたいな感じだけど。はい
This is so surreal. Like, "Go to the other side for once." Alright!
ジャジャジャジャーン！
Ta-ta-ta-ta-da!
ジャーン！黒色ー！
Ta-da! Black!
ジャーン。こっちが白で、こっちが黒。どうでしょう？
Ta-da. White here, and black here. What do you think?
最初とは違う色になってますけれども
It's a different color combination from the beginning, but...
まあ黒白ででもね、かっこいい感じ。シンプルだけどかっこいいみたいな感じで
well, black and white looks cool too. Simple yet cool,
色違いも作ってもらいましたー！
so I had different color variations made!
イェーイ！
Yay!
あ、で、スクショタイムだよね
Ah, and it's screenshot time, right?
さっき、こう、こうできたから...
Earlier was like this and like this, so...
こう？
Like this?
え、こう？
Wait, like this?
ダサすぎる！
That looks so uncool!
まあ、なんかいいようにしてください
Well, just make it look good however you like!
イェーイ！
Yay!
じゃ、んな感じでね
So, like that.
え、ということで、上が白黒、下が白黒ということでね
So, the top is white/black, and the bottom is white/black,
上と下をね、え、白黒白黒でね、好きな組み合わせにできる、え、衣装になっております
making this an outfit where you can mix and match white and black on top and bottom however you like!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はい。ではじゃあ、最初の服に戻ろうかな。少々お待ちください
Alright. Now then, let's change back to the first outfit. Please wait a moment.
チュチュチュチュチュ...
Chu chu chu chu...
ふぅ、この30キロの帽子と20キロのジャケットを着て...
Phew, putting on this 30 kg hat and 20 kg jacket...
で、服も塗り替えてまた、ペンキベタベタで戻ってきて...
and repainting the clothes, coming back all sticky with paint...
ふぅ
Phew.
はい！ということで
Alright! So,
最後、あ、ちょっと待って、最後ね。はい、これ
the last one... Ah, wait a sec, the last one. Alright, this.
最後、こ、こうか？こうじゃない？
The last one... is it like this? Isn't it like this?
こう？
Like this?
まあ、いいようにしてください
Well, just make it look good however you like.
はい
Alright.
ということで、いっぱい各色違いにスクリーンショットゾーンを撮ったんですけど
So, I took plenty of screenshot moments for each color variation,
どうでしたか？
how was it?
「TOWA」という文字を作りました！
I formed the letters "TOWA"!
是非！
Please!
どうぞ！何を？
Go ahead! ...With what?
何をどうぞって感じだったけど、まあ！
Like, "Go ahead with what?" but anyway!
ということで、こんな感じで新衣装はこういう風になっております！イェーイ！
So yeah, this is what my new outfit looks like! Yay!
いっぱいね、ハートとかね、いっぱい書いてくれたら嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you send lots of hearts and comments!
いつもありがとうございます！
Thank you as always!
ということで、この後は嬉しいお知らせとなりまーす！
And with that, next up is a happy announcement!
常闇トワ誕生日記念2026のグッズの発売決定！イェーイ！
The release of Tokoyami Towa Birthday Celebration 2026 merchandise has been decided! Yay!
こちらの配信後に発売開始となりますので、概要欄をチェックして待ってててくださいね
Sales will start right after this stream, so please check the description box and wait!
ということで
And so,
気になるグッズの詳細は、こちらをご覧ください！どうぞ！
for details on the merchandise you're curious about, check this out! Here you go!
うわー！うわー！
Whoaa! Whoaa!
うっ...よいしょっと
Oof... Oof-da.
え、ということで、えー...
So with that, uh...
イラストは美和野らぐ先生に描き下ろしていただきました！イェーイ！
the illustration was newly drawn by Miwano Rag-sensei! Yay!
可愛いでしょ、これ！
Isn't it so cute?!
え、旅行、お出かけをイメージして描いてもらいまして
Uh, I had it drawn with the image of traveling and going on an outing,
で、今回の新衣装を、え、モチーフとして、モチーフというか、新衣装で描いてもらいました！
and it features this new outfit as the motif—or rather, drawn in the new outfit!
そしてね、灯籠祭りや、え、ランタン祭り大好きなので、そちらをモチーフにしてもらってます！
And I love lantern festivals, so she used that as a motif!
よし、ということで、こっから立ってね、よいしょっと
Alright, so getting up from here... Oof-da.
はぁ...お待たせいたしました
Phew... Sorry to keep you waiting!
はい、ということで、この後というか、一つずつね...
Alright, so after this—or rather, one by one...
アイテムを紹介していきたいと思いまーす！
I'd like to introduce the items!
まずは、こちら！ どうぞ！ ドン！
First up, this one! Here you go, bam!
「願いを込めて。LEDアートパネル」！
"With a Wish: LED Art Panel"!
イェーーイ！
Yay!
このね、あの、MYAO先生に描き下ろしてもらったイラストを使って、
Using this illustration drawn by MYAO-sensei,
えー、アートパネルを作っちゃいましたー！
we made an art panel!
なんとこのアートパネル、LEDが入っておりますので、
And since this art panel has built-in LEDs,
ふんわり光っちゃいまーす！
it glows softly!
ちょっと美しい感じでしょ？
Doesn't it look kind of beautiful?
ぜひ、この際に手に入れてくださいねー。
Please be sure to get yours on this occasion!
はい！ そして2つ目はこちら、ボン！
Alright! And the second one is this, boom!
どっちのトワに... どっちのトワにする？
Which Towa... Which Towa will you choose?
「リバーシブルアクリルスタンド」ー！
"Reversible Acrylic Stand"!
はい、え、こちらはですね、この新衣装の、え、撮り下ろしとなっておりまして、
Yes. This one features newly shot visuals in this new outfit,
さっき色々帽子付けたりとか、こう上が黒だった、下が黒だ、
and earlier I showed you various color variations like wearing the hat,
上白だ、下が白だ、みたいな色々色違いを見せたと思うんですけども、
white top or white bottom, and so on...
それをね、ちゃんと表現してるアクリルスタンドになっております！
and this acrylic stand properly shows those variations!
表のトワちゃん、裏のトワちゃん、どっちもトワだ！
Front Towa-chan, back Towa-chan—they're both Towa!
ということで、こちらもぜひ見てくださいね。
So please check this out too!
はい、そして続いてはこちら！
Alright! And next up is this!
「新衣装モチーフキーホルダー」ー！
"New Outfit Motif Keychain"!
イェーイ！
Yay!
見てください、これですこれ。
Look, it's this one right here.
このトワのビビと、ほら、おりゃ、
Towa's Bibi and, look, here,
「TOWA」と書いたこのキーホルダーが、
this keychain that says "TOWA"...
このキーホルダーが、ここのアクセサリーがキーホルダーになっちゃいまーす！
This keychain—this accessory right here has turned into a keychain!
イェイイェイ！
Yay, yay!
はい、え、このね、モチーフにしてますので、ぜひお揃いで手に入れてみてください。
Yes. It's themed after my outfit, so please get it to match with me!
パーツはね、それぞれ取り外し可能になっております。
The parts are all detachable.
よろしくお願いいたします！
Thank you very much!
はい、そして最後はこちら、ボン！
Alright! And lastly, this one, boom!
「トワ様とお揃いキャップ」ー！
"Matching Cap with Towa-sama"!
イェーイ！
Yay!
このね、帽子とお揃いのキャップを発売することになりましたー！
We're releasing a cap that matches this hat!
普段使いしやすいデザインにもなってますので、
It's designed to be easy for everyday wear,
ぜひ今日、トワと一緒の帽子をつけたいなっていう方は購入してみてください！
so if you feel like wearing the same hat as Towa today, please check it out!
お願いしまーす！
Please do!
はい、ということで、こんな感じかな、紹介は。
Yes! So, that's about it for the merchandise showcase.
あっ、そうだった！ 戻る前に...
Ah, that's right! Before moving on...
この全部を買ったフルセット特典... あ、フルセット購入特典もあります！
The full set bonus for buying all of them... Ah, there's a full set purchase bonus!
忘れておりましたー！
I almost forgot!
え、フルセットをご購入いただいた皆さんには、
To everyone who purchases the full set,
箔押し複製サインと、あと今回はメッセージ入りポストカードをプレゼントしたいと思います！
we'll gift a postcard with a foil-stamped duplicate signature and a message!
ぜひフルセットで購入してみてください！
Please consider getting the full set!
はーい、よろしくお願いしまーす！
Alright, thank you very much!
はい、で、こっから... あっ！ そうだ、ここもまだここにいて...
Yes. And from here... Ah! That's right, stay right here...
なんとこれだけじゃないんですよ！ グッズだけじゃなくて、
That's not all! It's not just the goods...
あ、グッズは概要欄もチェックしてほしいのと、あと...
Ah, please check the description for goods info, and also...
そうなんです、最初のね、配信の最初に言ったと思うんですけれども、
That's right, as I mentioned at the beginning of the stream,
お知らせがまだ1個あるんですよ！
there is still one more announcement!
はい！ そのお知らせとは、こちら、ボン！
Yes! That announcement is this, boom!
新曲『SMASH IT UP』ーが、
My new song "SMASH IT UP"...
このあと24時から、0時になった瞬間からデジタルリリースされまーす！
will be digitally released starting tonight at 24:00, right at midnight!
イェーイ！
Yay!
いつもね、トワの楽曲とか作る時にすごいお世話になってるイソノさんっていう方がいらっしゃるんですけど、
Isono-san, who always helps me out so much when producing Towa's songs,
イソノさんにね、書き下ろしていただきましたー！
wrote and composed it for me!
なんかその、結構ざっくり『トワっぽい曲でお願いします』って。
I basically just asked vaguely, "Please make a Towa-esque song."
『トワっぽい』と、結構お世話になってるんですよ。
Since we work together a lot,
だからトワの音域とか、どういうのが得意かっていうのもすごい知ってくださってるので、
they know my vocal range and what style suits me best really well.
じゃあその、何か最大限に活かしたようなトワの曲を作ってくださいって言って
So I asked, "Please make a Towa song that makes the absolute most of that,"
できた曲が、『SMASH IT UP』なんですよね。
and the song that was born was "SMASH IT UP."
うーん。結構ね、
Yeah. It's quite...
なんか、でも来た時は、『トワ、トワ歌えるかな？ トワっぽいかな？
When I first received it, I was like, "Can Towa sing this? Is it Towa-esque?
え、でもこういうイメージ抱いてるんだな』っていう風な感じで、
Ah, so this is the image they have of me,"
すごい面白かったです。
which was super fun.
なんでね、でもね、不安だったんですよ、最初録るまでは。
So, yeah, I was a bit anxious until we actually recorded it.
でも録ってみたらすごい自分に合っててかっこいい曲になったので、
But once I recorded it, it fit me so well and became such a cool track,
ぜひ購入して聴いていただければなと思います。
so please buy and listen to it.
ダウンロードしてみてください！
Please download it!
はーい！
Alright!
はい、じゃあね、
Yes. So then,
『じゃあどんな曲なんだよ』って。『そんな、なんか』
you might wonder, "So what kind of song is it?
『もうゼロでダウンロードなんてできないよ』って思うじゃないですか。
I can't just download it blind with zero clue."
いやいや。
No, no.
今日はその、この発表した新曲で、本日のライブを締めくくりたいと...
Today, with this newly announced song, I'd like to wrap up today's live conc—
えっとここカットして...
Um, please cut this part...
ここカットしてって言ったけど、カットしなくていいですからね！
I said cut it, but you don't actually have to cut it, okay?
はい！ ではそんな新曲で本日のライブを締めくくりたいと思いまーす！
Yes! So I'd like to close out today's live concert with this new song!
いいですか？
Are you ready?
では、本日最後の曲です！
Here is the final song of today!
聴いてください！
Listen up!
SMASH IT UP
熱にあてられ
Affected by the heat,
熱を与えて
giving off heat,
シンクロしてくリズム 誇れ
be proud of the rhythm that syncs up.
くだらない境界
These stupid borders—
SMASH IT UP
溶けるように
As if melting away,
混ざり合っていく 本能と理性
instinct and reason blend together.
始めよう 再構築
Let's begin the reconstruction;
スポットライト頂戴
gimme the spotlight!
プロローグは必要ない
No prologue needed;
根拠なら目の前に
the proof is right before your eyes.
1人残らず巻き込むライオット
A riot that sweeps every single person in!
貫く覚悟 限界 黙殺しちゃうわ
Ready to push through, I'll just ignore my limits!
熱気が背中を押す
The fever pitch pushes me forward,
歌う 繊細豪快自在に
singing with delicate, bold freedom,
世界が無視できないくらい
so much that the world cannot ignore it!
影を踏み鳴らして
Stamping over shadows,
強くあれ 前のめりなBPM
stay strong in this headlong BPM!
狂気じみたプライド 抱いて
Embracing a mad pride,
くだらない境界
these stupid borders—
SMASH IT UP
凝り固まった価値観
Rigid values—
壊せ 壊せ 壊せ 壊せ
smash them, smash them, smash them, smash them!
絵空事だった歌詞が
Lyrics that once were mere pipedreams—
創る 創る 創る
I will create, create, create!
連動してく新境地
A newly reached ground connecting in sync,
揺れ動いちゃう心境も
and even my fluctuating emotions—
手懐け 壮大シンフォニー
I'll tame them into a grand symphony,
絡み合う コード 奏でる独壇場
intertwining chords playing my solo stage!
奏でる独壇場
Playing my solo stage!
答えはここに 何年経って歌うの
The answer is here—how many years will I keep singing?
貫く覚悟 限界 黙殺しちゃうわ
Ready to push through, I'll just ignore my limits!
熱気が背中を押す
The fever pitch pushes me forward,
歌う 繊細豪快自在に
singing with delicate, bold freedom,
世界が無視できないくらい
so much that the world cannot ignore it!
影を踏み鳴らして
Stamping over shadows,
強くあれ 前のめりなBPM
stay strong in this headlong BPM!
狂気じみたプライド 抱いて
Embracing a mad pride,
くだらない境界なんざ 追放だ
these stupid borders—banish them away!
SMASH IT UP
3D新衣装お披露目ミニライブ 8/8 sat. 21:00 告知アリ
[3D New Outfit Reveal Mini Live - Aug 8 (Sat) 21:00 with announcement]
3D新衣装お披露目ミニライブ 8/8 sat. 20:00 告知あり！
[3D New Outfit Reveal Mini Live - Aug 8 (Sat) 20:00 with announcement!]